<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home</title>
    <description>/home
</description>
    <link>https://rounakdatta.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://rounakdatta.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 20:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 20:06:49 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unleashing the best of IPFS</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/10/05/ipfs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/10/05/ipfs.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s behind an Ethereum TestNet?</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/10/05/ethereum-testnet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/10/05/ethereum-testnet.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Erlang - Making the best of Concurrency</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/10/05/erlang.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/10/05/erlang.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why CS Fundamentals matter</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/10/05/cs-fundamentals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/10/05/cs-fundamentals.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Flyr - Open-Source Bike-Sharing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/DHJytOc.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flyr is an open-source attempt to re-implement Lime, Bird or your favourite bike-sharing platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/NTWoC-2018-blue.svg&quot; alt=&quot;NTWOC&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-WTFPL-green.svg&quot; alt=&quot;WTFPL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tech-stack&quot;&gt;Tech Stack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;back-end&quot;&gt;Back-End&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microservices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phoenix Framework&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apache Kafka&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Redis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;front-end&quot;&gt;Front-End&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-will-be-my-commitments-for-this-project&quot;&gt;What will be my commitments for this project?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before coming to a conclusion, read the project README thoroughly. The project demands contributors who can be comfortable enough to write efficient server-side code (design); understand the fundamentals of each back-end component and integrate them; design efficient algorithms (shortest / best distance, dynamic pricing); create minimal and modular front-end for testing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This means being fundamentally strong in programming will allow you to quickly pick-up technologies and learn concepts. The process goes as disassemble -&amp;gt; understand -&amp;gt; re-write.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scalability and robustness is important. Building protoypes (MVP) are just 15% of a product. You should be able to realise the importance of your code being time and memory-efficient and non-breaking at edge-cases.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engineering the product involves understanding, designing and then coding. You should be able to realise the importance of logic (algorithm) before the code itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;should-i-apply-for-this-project&quot;&gt;Should I apply for this project?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are willing to take up this project seriously, you are more than welcome to apply.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s not totally essential to be accustomed with the technologies mentioned. If you are willing to spend the winter learning them and implementing them here as a side-project, you are welcome to apply.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This project has to be built from scratch, and everyone will be guiding everyone in the design, understanding and coding. If you’ve done this type of project before and you’re willing to mentor / help out contributors, you’re most welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re enthusiastic of this project, apply irrespective of whether you’re having the required skillset or not. You’ll definitely have a great learning curve.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your contribution to the project will matter even if it’s a documentation fix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Please note that this project will accept contributors irrespective of their being in 1st or 2nd or 3rd or 4th year.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-will-be-my-takeaways-from-the-project&quot;&gt;What will be my takeaways from the project?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll &lt;strong&gt;learn&lt;/strong&gt; a lot. Whichever responsibility you take up, your time investment will definitely yield a strong conceptual as well as practical understanding of the project components. Particularly, if you’ll be taking up
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Back-End Development, you’ll learn the core pieces of building a data pipeline, learn how microservices work, understand the importance of concurrency, will be confident regarding the choice of a DB system, experiment with streaming large amounts of data and afterall work will multiple existing open-source tools.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Front-End Development, you’ll write dynamically generated webpages with responsive text, maps, graphs, tables. Therefore involves a lot of API handling, XML HTTPRequests and UX magic.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Algorithms Development, you’ll be writing efficient algorithms after analyzing how existing systems work. Its fascinating to study and re-implement state-of-the-art algorithms and work them in action in the final product.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Integration &amp;amp; Testing, you’ll be responsible for connecting the pieces together - find out bottlenecks and scalability issues in the pipeline; also audit the product for breaking cases or security flaws.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll &lt;strong&gt;work as a team&lt;/strong&gt;, closely experience the building of software from scratch as multiple modules and integrating them together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;superb open-source project&lt;/strong&gt; - This is a promise from my side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discussions&quot;&gt;Discussions?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll have all conversations on Telegram. Join the group &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/joinchat/GGDDgg_EY8MgItxe7jLV7w&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/09/28/flyr.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/09/28/flyr.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Octolab.ML - The Automated Machine Learning Platform</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Octolab.ML is an automated machine learning platform to meet your daily statistical prediction needs. Free tier of the application allows your dataset to be
• &lt;b&gt;auto-cleaned&lt;/b&gt; • &lt;b&gt;auto-preprocessed&lt;/b&gt; • &lt;b&gt;predictions generated&lt;/b&gt; • &lt;b&gt;visualizations generated&lt;/b&gt;
when you supply us with the algorithm and other configurations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upload dataset
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn4.iconfinder.com/data/icons/ionicons/512/icon-arrow-right-b-128.png&quot; alt=&quot;Arrow&quot; class=&quot;img-center&quot; /&gt;
Select ML Algorithm
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn4.iconfinder.com/data/icons/ionicons/512/icon-arrow-right-b-128.png&quot; alt=&quot;Arrow&quot; class=&quot;img-center&quot; /&gt;
Additional configurations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Designed and developed keeping in mind a beginner’s difficulty in understanding machine learning frameworks.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/octolab.png&quot; alt=&quot;Octolab Landing Page&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;You should definitely try out &lt;a href=&quot;http://octolab.ml/&quot;&gt;Octolab&lt;/a&gt; right now!&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And don’t forget to also check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://nimblebox.ai/&quot;&gt;NimbleBox.ai&lt;/a&gt;, a cloud deep learning platform for all your GPU needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/09/22/octolab.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/09/22/octolab.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Digital Assistant - Automation to power E-Commerce</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How impressive was &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.googleblog.com/2018/05/duplex-ai-system-for-natural-conversation.html&quot;&gt;Google Duplex&lt;/a&gt;? Google Duplex can help you manage your daily routines by subsituting your monotonous actions with AI. Right from booking appointments to ordering goods, Google Duplex promises to handle them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What’s this Digital Assistant?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital Assistant aims to be the replacement for your conventional store managers. Whether its the task of enquiring for avaailable products, natural conversation regarding an item, bargaining for the price of a product, ordering the product, cancellation and grievance addressal or just simply chatting around, Digital Assistant aims to be your ultimate philosopher, friend and guide solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Where is it?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legen-wait-for-it-dary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ykkW85s.png&quot; alt=&quot;Digital Assistant Demo&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/09/22/digitalassistant.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/09/22/digitalassistant.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quill Audits - Smart Contract Security Analysis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Quill Audits is a smart contract analysis platform provided by QuillHash Technologies. It’s a fully automated platform for getting smart contracts checked for security vulnerabilities as well as efficiency of code. &lt;strong&gt;Oyente&lt;/strong&gt; for Ethereum is currently a trusted automated open-source smart-contract analysis tool. Quill Audits uses tweaked Oyente back-end with other sophistications to analyze contracts under-the-hood and return analysis results. Also, it uses &lt;strong&gt;Solidity-Coverage&lt;/strong&gt; to provide code coverage tools to analyze if there are are redundant lines of code by running unit tests. Often, redundant lines of code are required to be replaced / removed. Quill Audits is powered by Node.js and is an extremely fast and usable tool for smart contract security analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quill Audits platform provides for manual auditing as well. The platform also provides an escrow platform to request for expert contract auditing at the least bid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*fVizVy5bQ9j-845RwXjhBg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Quill Audits Architecture&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve also wrote a Medium article &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/quillhash/quill-audits-the-smart-contract-security-audit-platform-9ea1950ad6e&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/07/21/quillaudits.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/07/21/quillaudits.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ResXme - The ultimate resume parsing tool</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;ResXme is a resume-parsing tool built to automate the process of resume classification based on required criteria. ResXme tries to utilise the best of open-source softwares available to improve &lt;b&gt;accuracy&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;scalability&lt;/b&gt;. The core architecture of ResXme works on techniques of information mining from rich text resources, store them efficienctly and help them to be retrived with speed. The entire model is built as a web-app powered by Flask (Python) backend. Uses open-source NLP libraries like SpaCy, NLTK as well as NoSQL databases to &lt;i&gt;power and scale&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vr1nYID9xD0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/06/21/resxme.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/06/21/resxme.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CorrectLy - The Grammar Engine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;CorrectLy is a &lt;b&gt;English language and grammar-correction engine&lt;/b&gt;. CorrectLy’s favourite competitor is Grammarly. Uses core NLP as well as deep learning techniques to correct spelling errors, verb-noun agreements, verb-preposition-noun agreements, understand sentence context and help suggest more natural sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/maVkhZotEVM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/06/21/correctly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rounakdatta.github.io/2018/06/21/correctly.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
